Reid Wagner

reid.ab.wagner@gmail.com • 734 649 6143 • Los Angeles, CA • https://github.com/reidwagner/

Summary

I'm a DevOps software engineer with a physics and mathematics background interested in moving into a full developer role. The combination of my degree with the technical experience of DevOps provides a well-rounded knowledge base that I draw on to understand topics from algorithmic complexity or encryption schemes, to process signals and native threading. But, more than just understanding these structures I want to build them. Topics that interest me include but are not limited to operating systems, compilers, cloud computing, and web development.

Experience

Software Engineer — Thomson Reuters

Jan 2016 – Present (2yr 2mo)

- As team expert in Git, after leading group in transition from VSS, mediate any severe repository issues and strategize code branching.
- Created and manage custom HTTP request log analyzer and plotter for pinpointing problematic services or request origins.
- Contribute and debug application Java code for DevOps needs.
- Resolve highly technical issues that arise in administration of RHEL servers by researching kernel internals.
- Was key contributor in the migration of entire Production environment and the upgrade of all core technologies shortly thereafter.

Junior Scientist — U. of Minnesota Physics and Astronomy

Sep 2014 - Sep 2015 (1 yr)

- Optimized spacial, mass, stress, and thermal considerations through design and simulation for cosmological microwave telescope.
- Wrote Visual Basic to operate on large SolidWorks CAD assemblies.
- Worked with custom Python data analysis libraries.
- Designed and built aluminum and steel 12-foot educational demonstration.

Research Intern — Engineo Co., Ltd.

Jan 2013 - Aug 2013 (4 mo)

Assisted in sales and installation of solar panel and wind turbine energy systems.

Carried out experiments including comparison of efficiency of different charge controllers and the cooling of high-power LEDs.

Research Intern — U. of Michigan Materials Science and Engineering

June 2009 - Aug 2009 (3 mo)

- Worked in graduate lab to develop methods of visualising higher-dimensional data.
- Generated data sets in MATLAB with various mathematical and engineering models.
- Rendered data sets in IDL with techniques incorporating 3D color gradients.

Peer Consultant — Kalamazoo College Math-Physics Center

Oct 2013 - June 2014 (8 mo)

Guided students through studying and homework for college math and physics.

Projects, open source and personal

Micropython

- Implemented recalculation of select.poll timeout. (merged)
- Fixed bug where small timeouts rounded to zero. (merged)
- Implemented built-in deque object. (not merged, but still proud)

JSONfs

- Userspace file system utilizing FUSE Linux kernel module.
- Persists data as hierarchical JSON structure.
- Can successfully host its own development.

TSE780

- Zilog Z80 Emulator Written in C.
- Supports 164 unique opcodes.

x86 Kernel

- Bootloader implemented from scratch in Intel x86 assembly.
- IRQ-based PS/2 keyboard driver.
- VGA terminal driver.

Other

- REST service written in Hy (Lisp dialect of Python).
- cURL, working with maintainers on an open PR.
- $\mbox{stm}32\mbox{f4}$ MacOS CLI toolchain and flashing tutorial.
- Qubit emulation written in Haskell.
- Smaller contributions to further Github projects including Prost, sshfs, WAScan.

Technical Knowledge

Proficient in: C, Python, Bash/Unix shell, Java

Technologies: Linux and utils, POSIX, JBoss EAP, EJB, Git, Cygwin, Vim, Eclipse, Ant, Maven, Rundeck, Jenkins, Ansible, Wireshark, SSL/TLS, Openstack, Solidworks (CAD), TeX, 3D Printing, AWS, EC2, HTML, CSS, SQL

Education

Kalamazoo College

Bachelors in Physics and Mathematic

2010 - 2014

Aug 2012 - Feb 2013

Bachelors in Physics and Mathematics, with honors in Physics International Sustainable Development Studies Institute

Study abroad program in Chiang Mai, Thailand

Awards

John Wesley Hornbeck Prize - Awarded to senior with highest achievement for the year's work in advanced physics major.

Beeler Fellowship - Awarded to fund senior thesis abroad.

Founders Merit Scholarship - Awarded to students who combine strong academic achievement with significant engagement in co-curricular, work, and voluntary activities.

Honors in Physics Degree